# **ALEX LING**

# **EDUCATION**

09/2014 - 05/2018 NEW YORK UNIVERSITY (3.812/4.0)

New York, NY Gallatin School of Individualized Study

Individualized Major focused on design, art history, visual culture, and marketing

Minor: Business of Entertainment, Media, and

Technology (Stern School of Business)

COURSES Design Studio // Contemporary Visual Culture and the

Politics of Images // Entertainment & Media Industries // Media, Technology, and Society // Creative Computing //

Communications Lab // Digital Art and New Media

ACTIVITIES Founder and President of Gallazine

**Emerging Leader Award** 

Dean's List

08/2016 - 12/2016 **NEW YORK UNIVERSITY SHANGHAI** (4.0/4.0)

Shanghai, China Study Abroad: General Curriculum and

Interactive Media Arts

#### EXPERIENCE

09/2017 - Present New York, NY

# NYU GALLATIN // Graphic Designer

// Responsible for designing *The Literacy Review* Vol. 16 set for release in Spring 2018, related promotional content, and design needs for the Gallatin Writing Center

01/2017 - 08/2017 New York, NY

## AMINO APPS // Design Intern

// Design and illustrate app icons, mobile assets, and iOS and Android screenshots for app stores
// Social media rebrand of Instagram (400K+ to 700K+ followers in three months), design ad campaigns, graphics and animations for social media, mobile UI mockups
// Assist with promotional designs for product updates,
"Amino VIP" branding, deck templates, Amino style guide, and creating a cohesive image across all Amino platforms
// Organize Amino-wide fanart contest, reach out to artists to feature fan content on Amino, photo retouch art and community content

02/2016 - 06/2016 New York, NY

#### **VISIT.ORG** // Visual Editor Intern

// Curate, edit, and upload images to WordPress for organization pages, organize images, design decks

02/2015 - 06/2015 New York, NY

#### SCHOLASTIC // Art Dept Admin Assistant

// Invoice and record-keeping, contract editing, sample warehouse ordering

// Image and photo research, assemble prototypes, create "child-like" drawings and handwriting for products

07/2013 - 08/2013 New York, NY

# THE MET // Education and Digital Media Intern

// Edit thumbnail images for new audio guides // Verify, organize, and tabulate content from 10+ audio guides with 100+ audio guide tour stops

// Create and lead group gallery tour and discussion

EMAIL: aswling@nyu.edu
PHONE: (908) 399-5353
LOCATION: NY // NJ

### PROFILE

Hi! I'm Alex. I'm currently a senior at NYU's Gallatin School of Individualized Study where I'm pursuing an individualized major concentrating in design, art history, and marketing, specifically the ways to best visually communicate ideas and narratives. I'm also minoring in BEMT at NYU's Stern School of Business. I have professional experience in design, making creative content, and visual curation. In my free time, I'm usually found drawing comics and working on my UI/UX skills.

WEBSITE LINKEDIN PORTFOLIO GITHUB INSTAGRAM aswling.com /alexandraling @alexswling /aswling @aswling

#### **SKILLS**

Photoshop Illustrator InDesign Premiere Audacity HTML/CSS JavaScript Arduino InVision PaintTool SAI



## FAVE PROJECTS

<u>Skin Deep</u> (2016)

Amino Instagram Rebrand (2017)

FEED Magazine (2017)

Through the Bund (2016)

Zàijiàn (2016)

Homecoming (2017)

Of Mice and Men (2017)